Finding aid for the William Bast papers LSC.2290
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2. Feature film productions, 1967-1968
  - The Betsy (Allied Artists, 1978)
    - Final shooting script, September 6, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1977-1978 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Legal, 1977-1979 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Contains material regarding screen credits and residuals.
    - Notes, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Hammerhead (Columbia, 1968)
    - Revised final draft screenplay, August 22, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - The Valley of Gwangi (Warner Bros., 1969)
    - Incomplete screenplay "Gwangi the Great", April 3, 1967 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Includes storyboards.
    - Screenplay "Gwangi the Great", undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
- Series 3. Unproduced material, 1962-2002
  - Alamo Run
    - Agreements and notes, 1991 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - And Presumed Dead / Silhouette
    - Scripts based on the novel by Lucille Fletcher, 1968-1990 (Box 65, Folder 8-9, Box 66, Folder 1-2)
    - Da Costa, Morton -- correspondence, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Barnaby Jones (CBS, 1973-1980)
    - Scripts, 1973 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - The Bermuda Triangle
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 5-7)
  - Best of Both Worlds
    - Treatment by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Best of Friends / Lesbian Story
    - Script material and agreements, 1976 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Beyond Tomorrow
    - Treatments and research, 1971-1972 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Includes transcripts of the Walter Cronkite-hosted radio program The Twenty-First Century.
  - The Birdcage
    - Scripts and agreements, 1968-1973 (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
  - Breakdown
    - Script material, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Circle of Fear (NBC, 1972-1973)
    - Script, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Code Three
    - Teleplay, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Coming Out / Quean [sic] for a Day
    - Scripts, 1978-1979 (Box 67, Folder 7, Box 68, Folder 1-6)
    - Correspondence and legal, 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Research, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Contains: Gay Source by Dennis Sanders (New York: Coward, McCann & Geoghegan).
    - Research - periodicals, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Contains: The Advocate, 7/27/1977; Gay Sunshine, Summer/Fall, 1977; Publishers Weekly, August 8, 1977; Blueboy, November, 1977.
    - Research - clippings and flyers, 1977-1979 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - A Cry in the Jungle
    - Outline by Samuel Marx, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - The Dolly Sisters
    - Research, 1912-1970 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Dreadnought
    - Script material by William Bast and Elliot Silverstein, 1969-1970 (Box 69, Folder 6-7, Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Research, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
      Contains material about ships and sailing.
  - Fanny Kemble
    - Script materials and correspondence, 1996 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      Much of the correspondence discusses gaining Jane Seymour's interest in the project. Although there is no evidence of direct correlation, Seymour played Fanny Kemble in Enslavement (Showtime, 2000).
  - Frankenstein
    - Script material by William Bast & Paul Huson and Steve Berman, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 1-3, Box 70, Folder 4-6)
    - Agreements, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Novel, 1981 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      Contains Frankenstein by Mary Shelley (New York: Bantam Books).
    - Research, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Ghost Riders
    - Script by Paul Huson and William Bast, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Girl in the Red Velvet Swing
    - Research, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      Contains Evelyn Nesbit and Stanford White: Love and Death in the Gilded Age by Michael Macdonald Mooney [photocopy].
  - Grand Central
    - Outlines by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1998 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1998 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Research, 1998-1999 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - The Guests
    - Scripts by George Edwards and Curtis Harrington, 1969 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - The Harlem Hellfighters
    - Research and outlines by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1991-1995 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Hawaii Five-O (CBS, 1968-1980)
    - Script, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - High Flight / All Through the Night
    - Outlines by William Bast & Paul Huson based on the autobiography by Ian Simms, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Agreements, 1999-2002 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Book, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Contains High Flight by Ian T. Simms (Xlibris) [two copies, one hardcover inscribed by the author].
  - In Our Time
    - Outline and correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      Includes letters wondering if The Land of Hope (CBS, 1976) infringed on this property.
  - Interview with the Vampire
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson based on the novel by Anne Rice, 1984-1985 (Box 73, Folder 7-8, Box 75, Folder 1-5, Box 74, Folder 1-6, Box 76, Folder 1-4)
    - Agreements, 1984-1985 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Casting, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1984-1985 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Novel, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      Contains Interview with the Vampire by Anne Rice (New York: Ballantine Books).
  - It's Not Nice to Fool Mother Nature
    - Outlines by William Bast and Arthur Hoffe, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Jack and Jackie
    - Scripts based on books by Mary Van Rensselaer Thayer, 1978-1991 (Box 78, Folder 1, Box 77, Folder 2-6)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1980 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes photocopies and transcripts of letters from Jackie Kennedy to Mary "Molly" Van Renssaelaer Thayer; correspondence with Dave Powers, the former Special Assistant to President Kennedy.
    - Research, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      Contains Jacqueline Kennedy: The White House Years by Mary Van Rensselaer Thayer (Boston: Little, Brown) [photocopy]
    - Research, 1961 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      Contains Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy by Mary Van Rensselaer Thayer (Garden City: Doubleday) [photocopy]
    - Research, 1961 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      Contains Portrait: The Emergence of John F. Kennedy by Jacques Lowe (New York: McGraw Hill) [photocopy].
    - Research, 1965 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Contains My Twelve Years with John F. Kennedy by Evelyn Lincoln (New York: David McKay) [photocopy].
    - Research - clippings and notes, 1961-1980 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Research - Fay Weldon notes, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
      These are dozens of photocopies of handwritten notes. Their relation to Fay Weldon is unknown.
    - Research - note cards, undated (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Research - script, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Contains final draft teleplay Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy (ABC, 1981) by Steven Gethers.
  - Judy
    - Scripts, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 4-6, Box 80, Folder 1-2)
    - Casting, 1979 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes audiocassette "Peter Allen 'Quiet Please' for Judy."
    - Note cards, undated (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Production notebook, 1978-1979 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Research, 1977-1978 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      Contains material about Judy Garland, including photographs.
  - King Tut / The Love God
    - Scripts, 1978-1980 (Box 82, Folder 1-6, Box 83, Folder 1-3, Box 81, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1999 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      Includes two letters from Katherine Helmond; letter from Karel Reisz.
    - Note cards, undated (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Research and story notes, 1977-1979 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      Includes character sketches.
  - The Last Mogul
    - Scripts, 1989 (Box 84, Folder 1-3)
    - Research, 1987-1989 (Box 84, Folder 4)
      Includes transcript of oral history with Gladys Nederlander about her marriage to Milton Rackmil.
  - Last Rites
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 5-6)
    - Agreements and clippings, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Living with Lies
    - Outlines by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1999-2000 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Lotus Land
    - Scripts, 1984-1985 (Box 87, Folder 1-2, Box 85, Folder 2-6, Box 86, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      Includes cable from Carolyn See, John Espey, and Lisa Kendall aka Monica Highland; letter from CBS Standards and Practices objecting to racial epithets and sex.
    - Note cards, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Novel, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 5)
      Contains Lotus Land by Monica Highland (New York: Coward-McCann) [annotated].
  - Mammy and Lillie
    - Treatments, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Note cards, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Research - Lillie Hitchcock Coit, 1955 and undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Research - Mary Ellen Pleasant, 1974 and undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Research - San Francisco, 1962-1976 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Marriage of the Century
    - Screenplay based on a story by Edward Dmytryk, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Miracle in the Blizzard
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1993 (Box 88, Folder 8, Box 89, Folder 1-2)
    - Agreements, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Interviews, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      Seven audio cassette tapes.
    - Notes, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Research, 1987-1988 (Box 89, Folder 6-7)
      Contains material about the crash of Continental Airlines flight 1713, including an annotated copy of the NTSB report.
  - Mod Squad (1968-1973)
    - Teleplay, 1971 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - The Movie Set
    - Treatments, 1984-1985 (Box 90, Folder 2-6, Box 91, Folder 1-2)
    - Agreements, 1984-1985 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Notes, undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Novel, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 5-6, Box 92, Folder 1-2)
      Contains manuscript by June Flaum Singer.
  - Night of the Dead
    - Screenplay based on a story by Joseph Stefano, Curtis Harrington and George Edwards, 1973 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - No Shoulder for My Tears / A Shoulder for My Tears
    - Scripts, 1973 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Oltmans' Kennedy project
    - Correspondence and research, 1978-1981 (Box 92, Folder 5)
      Includes Gallery, April 1978; correspondence with Willem Oltmans [in one letter Oltmans indicates that Oliver Stone is involved with the project].
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 92, Folder 6)
      Typed manuscript of Willem Oltmans' book on the John F. Kennedy assassination.
  - One Hundred Years from Now / If I Should Wake Before I Die
    - Outlines and research, 1972 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - The Paladin
    - Scripts based on the novel by Brian Garfield (Box 95, Folder 1-2, Box 94, Folder 1-5, Box 93, Folder 2-5)
    - Notes and agreements, 1983-1984 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - The Patriot / Pursuit
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1987 (Box 95, Folder 4-6, Box 96, Folder 1-5)
    - Notes and research, 1987 (Box 96, Folder 6)
      FILE CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials in this file will require assessment for safe access. To review these digital materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
      Includes 5.25" floppy disk.
  - Pearls
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson from the novel by Celia Brayfield, 1994-1999 (Box 97, Folder 1-6, Box 98, Folder 1-7)
    - Agreements, 1993-1995 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Brayfield, Celia - correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Budgets, 1994-1996 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Flach Film, 1995-1999 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Notes, 1994-1997 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Novel, 1987 (Box 100, Folder 1)
      Contains Pearls by Celia Brayfield (London: Penguin Books).
  - Power / Tanz auf dem Vulkan / Place de l'Etoile
    - Outlines by William Bast & Paul Huson and Joseph Hardy, 1992-1994 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Agreements, 1993-1994 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Notes, 1991-1993 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - The Prisoner (ITC, 1967-1968)
    - First draft teleplay "Girl of My Dreams", August, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - The Prisoner
    - Script by Roderick Taylor, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Private Property
    - Scripts, 1973-1974 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Rhoda's Raiders / The Lightfinger Ladies
    - Outlines and research, 1970-1972 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Rosemary's Son / Spawn of the Devil
    - Outlines by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1972 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Scapegoat
    - Outlines and research, 1999-2003 (Box 101, Folder 3)
      Contains material about Herschel Grynszpan.
  - Second Chance
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 4-9, Box 102, Folder 1-3)
    - Agreements, 1988-1989 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Notes and outlines, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Seven Steps to the Moon
    - Script, undated (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Simon Bolivar
    - Correspondence and notes, 1998-1999 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Spoils of War
    - Script, undated (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - The Starrs of Texas
    - Agreements, 1993-1994 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Stolen Time
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1991-1992 (Box 102, Folder 10-11, Box 103, Folder 1-3)
    - Agreements, 1991 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1991-1992 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Tender Loving Lies / Daddy's Girl
    - Scripts by Fred Walton and Norman Morrill and William Bast & Paul Huson, 1991-1993 (Box 103, Folder 6-8)
    - Agreements and notes, 1992-1993 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Tongues of Fire
    - Scripts by William Bast and Paul Huson, 1988-1989 (Box 105, Folder 1-4, Box 104, Folder 1-8)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - A Touch of Magic / Autobiography of a Witch / Jean Stapleton Special
    - Scripts, 1976-1977 (Box 105, Folder 6-7, Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Agreements and notes, 1977 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      Includes playscript Bell, Book and Candle by John van Druten (New York: Dramatists Play Service, 1951).
  - Towers of Manhattan / Manhattan Towers
    - Scripts by William Bast & Paul Huson, 1994 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Trouble in Paradise
    - Scripts by William Bast & Paul Huson and Sara Davidson, 1984-1985 (Box 106, Folder 4-7)
    - Agreements, 1984 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - The Ultra Secret
    - Scripts by Paul Wheeler and William Bast from the book by F.W. Winterbotham, 1977-1978 (Box 107, Folder 1-6, Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Agreements and notes, 1977-1979 (Box 108, Folder 2)
      Includes script notes from Richard Fleischer and Joseph Shaftel; audiocassette.
  - Une chose de mort
    - Script, undated (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - The Uninvited
    - Agreements, 1989-1998 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Voleur
    - Treatments by William Bast and David Sheehan based on an unpublished novel by Ronald Jay Bass, undated (Box 108, Folder 5-6)
  - Voyage to the Bottom of the Sea (ABC, 1964-1968)
    - Outlines, 1964 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Washington Square
    - Scripts by William Bast and William Hanley based on the novel by Henry James, 1979-1980 (Box 108, Folder 8-9, Box 109, Folder 1-4)
    - Agreements, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Novel, 1977 (Box 109, Folder 6)
      Contains Washington Square by Henry James (Harmondsworth: Penguin Books) [one annotated photocopy and two paperbacks, one annotated].
  - We Have Always Lived in the Castle
    - Notes and agreements, 1991-1992 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Western No. 1
    - Script, 1967 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Winners and Losers
    - Outline by John D. Hess, based on the novel Sow Not in Anger by Jack Hoffenberg, 1976 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - You Can't Win 'em All
    - Script, undated (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Unused stories
    - Outlines and notes, 1962-1976 (Box 110, Folder 4-7)
- Series 4. General files, 1953-2005
  - Clippings and ephemera, 1971-1997 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    Includes schedule for Equicon 76/Filmcon 4.
  - Correspondence, 1958-1974 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    Includes copy of a letter to Dimitri Mitropoulos, October 26, 1958; two letters from Colin Wilson, May, 1959; two letters from John Valva, Roddy McDowall's companion on the set of Cleopatra (1963), 1962; copies of two letters to Ingo Preminger about Bunny Lake Is Missing, 1962.
  - James Dean, 1973-2005 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    Includes clippings; inquiries from fans and would-be biographers; questionnaires with William Bast's responses; proposal for a book of Sanford Roth photographs, with text by William Bast and Paul Huson.
  - James Dean - legal, 1957-1993 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    Contains material about William Bast's first biography of Dean; royalty report; correspondence regarding publication in Japan and re-publication in the United States.
  - "Letters from the Family", 1953-1958 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    Contains what appears to be an epistolary short story.
  - Notes and ideas, 1958-1959 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    Includes essays describing Igor Stravinsky conducting Oedipus Rex at Royal Festival Hall with Jean Cocteau reading his text.
  - "Show the Nice Lady Your Tail, Daniel", 1958 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    Contains drafts of a short story.